Well, here it is, if we are on the audience, it was just to address the council on any agenda items.
Now would be the time.
There are being none.
Item four is consent agenda.
Staff is recommending items five through 24 for the consent agenda.
There are no questions on those items that entertain emotion.
Question those.
We do have to pull off the children for the Coleman.
And which number was that please?
Nineteep.
Okay.
So,
Excluding item 19, then staff is recommending items five through 24.
Excluding item 19.
Motion to a Primer.
And a second.
Roll call.
Johnson.
Lewis.
Hi.
Short.
And are we just taking the action on 19?
No.
On 19, we had to take a separate action because we have to have the motion indicate that it is
Wording the contract to service solutions.
Okay.
So,
I am going to on item 19 make the motion that we award bid number C 17 dash 14 to
Service solutions for the purchase and installation of a
Chiller at the Coleman Theatre in the amount of 72,738.
And 44 cents.
Do we have a second?
No.
I'll second it.
The roll call.
Short.
Nice.
Johnson.
Hi.
I'm 25.
Cultural district development grant award.
Marsha.
Hi, Marsha.
I just saw Marsha at the Health Department.
Garden Park.
What about the wine for a second?
Well, we had our garden party and invited some of the heads of the
different organizations that partnered with us to create this
garden.
And it's going very well.
We have plans to expand it.
And we've been doing classes.
I was out there today with a group from the Boys and Girls
Club.
And we plan to do some special children's gardens with the upcoming grant.
So, we're.
So, next year early in the year, can you give us a presentation that we can
put on the board?
Because I know you've talked about expanding that into in-field lots.
I would be happy to.
Before the planning season starts, make the public aware.
Okay.
All right.
I'll talk about the social district.
Okay.
On April the 5th, you passed a resolution recognizing a cultural district
as proposed by the Miami Arts and Humanities Council to the Oklahoma Arts Council.
And annual came before you and she presented a map of the district,
which I've given you that in your packets.
She also informed you what a cultural district is, which is basically a mixed use
pedestrian-friendly area that has focus on arts and cultural facilities and events
in that area that kind of serves as an anchor to bring the community and tourists in.
But she also pointed out research that demonstrates the economic value of such a cultural
district and in fact a recent economic impact study has compelling evidence that for the
state of Oklahoma, the arts have brought in $300 million in one year and of course that
includes the impact of cultural tourism.
Grant funds, which I'm happy to tell you that we did receive the grant, we just found out
on July the 8th, it was, it was while I was at the party radio, it was right after you left,
but annual call man, she said that she had just found out that she had just found out
that we got the grant.
The grant funds received this year will be used to help us to develop a cultural district
plan and then also to market the district and brand the district.
Now the total funding was originally announced at $25,000 over the course of five years
with no more than 7,500 in any given year because of cuts at the state level, it's a little
bit less than that this year, I don't think they've told us what the total will be overall,
but regardless of the amount of the money we see this grant as being something we can leverage
to attract additional funding to our district.
Also, I will tell you that the cultural district fits in with the city's comprehensive plan
and with the city manager's budget message for this year.
In the competence of plan, it highlights the impact that the arts, culture and creativity
can have on the quality of life and a community.
It's a kind of thing for us that makes us fall in love with our community, but it also attracts
others who want to come to our community as well.
And in the city manager's budget message, he mentions four elements of the comprehensive plan
and then talks about some of the budget initiatives to address those and under two of those,
he mentions this under element one, which talks about the quality and character of the city's
different districts, such as the commercial district, but also such as key corridors like Main Street
that the city was cooperating with Arts and Humanities Council to create this cultural district,
and it would enhance the quality and the character of Main Street.
And then further under another element element three, where he talks about protection and management
of sensitive natural and cultural resources.
He talks about how the district will help with that as well.
So we are very excited to get started on this and I'll be glad to answer any questions if you
haven't had this time.
And tonight are we just voting to accept the grant award and I know we, it's really, this is just
a presentation.
I'll tell you that we're voting at last.
I want to make sure.
We're just happy we got this.
I'm excited.
I'm just excited.
I'm just excited about downtown in general.
No.
Okay.
Do we have them?
Well, I guess we don't need a vote.
So, Marshall, thank you.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
Item 26 is up, they don't splash pad grant, James.
How are you tonight?
Good.
I was going to give you quick update on the splash pad with DQ being involved for, they, we had
meeting with them.
The C1 was on, on June 29, we had a meeting with DQ, they said they was going to start
their process in January of helping us remove the bill.
I also got a Susan Henry, she's with Oklahoma Tourism Department, who we got to grant
through.
I updated her on that, stating that DQ is involved helping us with the removal of the
building in about our April 30th, 2017 deadline, how we wouldn't be able to meet that.
She said she is fine with that.
She said she would get that in a ride.
Yes.
That was a big thing I was worried about when she thought, when I talked to her, she said,
with having several other agencies involved, just keep a progress report, which we've already
started that.
And she said that allows them to know where we're at, where they're at, keep everyone on the same
page.
We've also put in a certified letter to the State Historical Prevention Office in Oklahoma Art College
and surveyed, we did get one back from the State Historical Deal.
They need a little further information on the building itself.
They want to know the architect and all that, who built it.
So we've got to dig all that stuff up, send it back into them, as far as them.
They said that'll give them 30 days to review that, and once they're 30 days they'll give us
our letter, we can't either get your name.
We also got with the Pure Tribe since the building is actually in the Pure Ignation area.
They actually have to say, whether they have any concerns or whatever, we got with them, they're
working on it right now.
So as soon as we get those three things back, we'll send it back into Oklahoma Tourism, and
when they give us the final goal, we'll have a site inspection at the site, and they want
everybody there.
So we can go over there as far as all the handicapped accessible and shaving and all that that they
want.
So that's where we're at right now.
So Susan, you know, like she said, she goes, just keep a progress report, and to let everybody
know what's on the same page.
So, you know, she said even as of right now, if she was to give us the go, go ahead date,
we still wouldn't be able to complete it anyways, as far as the April 30th.
It's for all the red tape and stuff that we have to cross.
So, so James, I know what the building coming down, and that's where we're looking at putting the
splash pad.
If we've done any preliminary drawings of other parking, intrinsic or things like that for the
ball park area, we're just getting started on that.
And in fact, Jamie, I think you were included on it, but just today we've received the memorandum
of understanding from ODEQ.
for the demolition of the building.
We're going to be involved in a to some extent, for example,
and demolishing the building, they can't demolish it
unless the light fixtures are removed because of the mercury
and the light fixtures.
So we're going to have to be responsible for taking out the light fixtures.
Now, we might just put them in one of the garage bays
in the building and somebody will haul them off,
or we have to do some things like that.
Also, as you know, there is that kind of that chloramine type
plume that's there.
And again, ODQ is saying that once the building is removed,
that plume will start to dissipate,
but they'll have to have a well-volved there,
where they'll keep a sump pump.
And we're going to continue to maintain the sump pump
and keep electricity to that sump pump,
because that keeps the plume from spreading.
So that's going to take some time to dissipate that.
So we're going to have to design this
in such a way that the splash pad is far away from that as possible.
But the plan is that there's ample property out there.
The plume is not a very large one.
We're talking about over four acres that we're going to be opening up.
And the splash pad will include a restaurant facility as well.
So we want to tie that.
So it starts blending into the park that we already have there
around the ball field.
Another thing that we've been approached by a BMX,
they've expressed an interest possibly
in reloking the BMX park there.
And that makes a lot of sense.
They need an area about the size of the soccer field.
Soccer field.
Yes.
And if we had that in that area,
we would have the BMX where they could also
share the same rest in facility with the splash pad.
So there's a possibility of this growing into a very large recreational park
right in the center of town.
There's some really good prospects that we could have with this.
So we're discussing that.
So a lot of work that has to be done.
But as long as the state funding is available,
the state is really, the state has really stepped up and helped us on this.
And it's been a very positive experience.
I think people would be shocked at the number of visitors
our community just as resulted at BMX Park.
Exactly.
With that, we've always had opportunity to host state tournaments
there to the EMAX.
My MS has been number one in the state of Oklahoma.
In the last couple years, they've never been able to host that BMX
because they didn't have a bathroom.
With this, it's when we have a bathroom there
that they can actually start hosting state tournaments.
So this is just very much in the planning stages,
but there's some very good things that we could do here.
OK, James, thanks very much.
Thank you.
Questions, Biggie?
All right.
I'm 27 new business.
Any new business, anyone?
Not being?
No.
Not announcements?
I've been in my office, got one, because I think James won't follow up a little bit.
I asked Kobe Allen to be here at her in August 2nd meeting.
I asked him to come here to give us an estimate on replacing the state on sign out of
their own state on the billboard.
He's been giving us some numbers.
If you've seen the sign, it's really faded and it doesn't look very good.
So I'm going to have him come here and give us an estimate of what it calls for replace
that.
You know, I think Dean wants to follow up on the sign.
Well, following up on the sign, that intersection is going to be targeted for improvements
in the future.
The Intertrapal Council held a meeting about four months ago in which there was a discussion
both with the Oklahoma Turnpike Authority and O.D. of improving the intersection.
At 69A, the Turnpike and Steve Holmes Boulevard.
It's everybody knows you don't have protected left-hand turns when you come off.
The Turnpike, or when you're turning on 69A, and with the amount of traffic out there plus
the additional development that's potential in that area, that area with the signage could
potentially, we might have to look at moving that sign eventually.
The other thing is that often on there's been some discussions about with the Fullerton family
because they have property in that area and they're actively wanting to develop it.
And there was a question about the ownership.
I think it's been floating out there for quite some time.
We had a survey done in that area as part of these projects, and it shows very clearly that
that property is owned by the Turnpike Authority.
And in fact, even representatives of the Fullerton family were working very closely with, as part
of the survey, we came on a document dated in 1956, which basically, Judge Fullerton sold it
to the Turnpike Authority.
And that's when the Turnpike was being built in 1956.
So we've clarified that.
But for future development, what I'm hoping we can do is talk to the Turnpike Authority
in the past, and so it might remember, there was some discussion with the Turnpike Authority
about a large piece of property across the street from Steve Bowen's, immediately adjacent
to Ken's farm at home.
We might want to start that discussion with them again, because some of that property will be
needed when they do the intersection improvement.
But some of that property may also come into play when that area eventually develops.
If there's a development of Ken's farm in home, we might have to do something to be able
to accommodate that.
This is an intersection that is going to throw in the future.
And I think, I think, with well-state bank investing there, I think some of the tribes are
looking at some investments right at that intersection as well.
We're moving on waterline to accommodate a development that the Kualpa tribe is interested in.
It's going to become more and more congested.
So I think not only just improving the sign right now, which is something we have to do,
but I think we need to talk about a little better place to put that sign where it's not in traffic,
where it still stands.
out, our visitors can see it, it's still on her Steve, and it still says welcome to my
Anna, but someplace a little more permanent.
So I think that's something we're going to have to think about with you, Jim.
Congratulations.
I hope you'll have all the unknowns.
I asked him to put that in there.
What we asked him over if necessary.
So we'll have all that.
And we may do it in stages when they just refaced the sign now, because what I'm talking about
of the intersection could be several years before that gets taken care of.
Hey, anything else?
Did you have announcements?
Steve, city manager.
I just have one thing I wanted to talk about.
I'm going to ask Chief Anderson to come up, and that's been a tough time for police
officers nationwide.
Glenn, it was just telling me a little while ago that appears that there has been a shooting
in Kansas City just recently.
An officer, we don't have a lot of information, but it looks like it could be another one of those
shootings like they experienced in Dallas and they experienced a bad marriage.
We were kind of light-hearted about the donations that came in because it was just such a wonderful
thing that happened.
What's really going on right now, emotions are raw, it's getting to us the fact that our officers
are doing exactly what we're asking them to do, and they're being put in harm's way.
I think I've told you before, but I'm very familiar with Ferguson Missouri, having served in
Branson.
And I could tell you, if you read everything about Ferguson, that's not the police officers
fault.
In fact, if anything, the fault really lies with a city manager of Ferguson, and some of the things
he asked of his police department, that I would never do here.
But it's putting our officers in kind of a harm's way, and we just have to recognize the fact
that what they do on a daily basis, they're literally risking their lives.
They don't know what they're going to be walking into.
But I think we're just so grateful for the recognition that we've had in the community.
We are absolutely very grateful.
I know it was the day after the Dowl shooting, I've said it in my office, and I said something
that I want to talk to you, and that's usually a complaint or somebody that, you know, is not
happy.
And I went up front, and ladies and gentlemen, once we're made none of us asked me to bring this
to you, and I received a card with two 5,000 dollar jacks.
And they said that, you know, we support police department, and they just wanted to say,
thank you, and we're behind you, meeting behind you.
That was actually amazing.
Following day, I know the Friday, maybe Monday, I had another one.
I can't say I came in, and when I was crying, I said, hey, take my 5,000 dollar jack.
And we were just absolutely blown away by the generosity and the support of the community.
Now, the second check went to the criminal work.
It was to the fraternal workplace, and it went with a lot of good calls.
Every day, we've had people bring up.
Cookies, water, data rate, some dot-fact, and the community is absolutely supporting the place department.
That's just wonderful to see.
I credit that to our officers and their professionalism and the way they do their job.
And we're just ecstatic that the community has been behind us.
Last week, I was at an emergency management conference.
Chief Fundman called me.
I wanted to put the story in the paper on the donations.
And he asked, did you guys really get $15,000 donations?
Yes.
We're amazed.
He's a purely tribal like the Max lag.
And a pure tribe gave us another $15,000 for, just done it in support of the place department.
So it's very high in this.
So we wanted to say that we're very grateful to them and to the community.
It's very blessed.
All of our departments have far more needs than are in the budget.
And we've taken steps to ensure that those donations are going toward those needs that are not in the budget.
We want to make that very clear of that whenever we receive a donation, not just for the police, but anything along that line.
The donations we receive for the animal shelter, we're ensuring that those go above and beyond.
That's very important for our community to know that.
And I think just also just publicly just say thank you.
Absolutely.
I was.
Whoever was.
And all of them, say thank you and we appreciate support.
But it kind of highlights what's going on is, you know, how dangerous a lot of our work is.
Not just the police department.
I'm looking at Ronnie and Robert back there with our firefighters.
We're all of them.
We're all a team.
And when you, I'm looking at Tyler and our electric crews and how they're out there during storms and all that.
And what they're dealing with is extremely dangerous too.
So got a lot of good people.
Sometimes they're up to their arms.
Thank you.
Thanks, John.
Thanks, thank you.
Thank you.
Any other comments?
Very grateful for the donation.
Absolutely.
Either 30 is a German.
We have a lot of children.
Make a national adjourned.
Sir, roll call please.
Louis Johnson.
Hi.
I'm just off to sign here.
Yeah.
So I'm there.